go excellent all right okay okay thank
you guys for joining today we're gonna
be talking about cash fusion there was
no subtitle so I just made it up myself
so flexible arbitrary input
consolidation coin joints yeah let's see
here so this is the paper where we're
looking at it's it's available on github
the link is right here and I will also
post a pdf version in the wasabi
research site as well okay there we go
just a reminder where we are we've done
all of these things so far the last
three weeks actually the last four weeks
we've been concerned with coin shuffle
and coin shuffle plus plus which is a
good predecessor to cash Fusion and then
next week it looks like we're gonna be
doing cash Fusion again everything is
available on the github so let's just
remind ourselves what have we been
talking about well with coin shuffle and
coin shuffle plus plus the issue being
addressed is the one of removing the
coordinator so allowing individuals to
collaborate amongst themselves in a
trustless way given some bulletin board
that doesn't have any sort of
computation properties to it it's just a
bulletin board where people can gather
together and meet up with coin shuffle
there was this onion encrypting of
addresses and then having them shuffled
around sequentially across peers and we
talked about why something like Quin
shuffle might not scale scale very well
to many many participants but it works
well with a with a small number of
participants and a good example is
electron cache which has five
participants we then talked about coin
shell plus plus which adds to the
protocol by introducing a DC net that
can handle collisions and disruptions in
just four plus two F rounds given
have malicious peers and sorry I made a
mistake there should be malicious peers
so yeah so we've been talking about
these different ways of removing the
coordinator and making these coin joins
yeah so this week so let's start with
the problem so when users coin join with
cash shuffle or pretty much any protocol
they get usually many coins of equal
denominations back to them many clean
coins so with wasabi they would get
coins of 0.1 denominations if they're
using a different protocol it might be a
different denomination but overall they
they've they get many clean coins and so
we need a way to private a private way
for users to consolidate arbitrary
number of coins without revealing input
ownership that's pretty much what we're
looking for and the protocol should not
rely on a central coordinator apart from
something like a bulletin board and the
protocol should allow for arbitrary
outputs of arbitrary amounts so a person
to be able to have many inputs and and
many outputs okay so I just wanted to be
very clear about the problem and then
I'll have one of the authors who's with
us today
mahjongg all right yes sir okay great
okay he will answer our questions and
maybe say more about the protocol but
I'll just be very clear here about about
the other problem so what you're looking
at right now is tip is a typical you
know corn joint type structure where
three participants are getting together
and they have these equal output
denominations and in this case they have
one Bitcoin outputs and two bitcoin
outputs for example and then they have
some change remaining and if they have
changed remaining it means that they
likely wanted to have that change
further mixed in a different coin joint
round so you can imagine this is the
second coin joint now is built on top of
the first one where all of the users
change is now being used to further mix
those anonymous or the the unclean
changed and honestly and this continues
where people continuously
take their the change of a 1-point joint
and use that in a future point to mix
again
and if you wanted to spend that Bitcoin
for example let's say you wanted to
spend three Bitcoin and you're the
purple individual well then you would
have to pick your UT EXO's from these
multiple coin joints and use them to
consolidate into a single transaction to
spend the three bitcoins so the problem
that we have is that if you're this mr.
orange guy over here and you know I like
to visualize coin joints as almost like
a blockchain so just it's sequential and
you know coin joins happen in order
obviously because the blockchain is in
order so you can imagine that when
someone like this orange guy doesn't
coin join he participates at a certain
point in in this coin joint train or
this this block chain this chain of corn
joints and everyone in the world can see
that this person participated in a coin
joint you know if I gave orange some
money then I can watch us as orange
participates in a particular coin joint
and then further we can track as orange
participates in other coin joints but
the change by following where the change
goes now orange is not going to be able
to participate in all of the coin joins
whether it's because or in just laptop
falls asleep or because he falls asleep
or because he disconnects in one of the
rounds he's going to have a not
necessarily a hundred percent success
rate with coin joins they might be a bit
scattered and so after the there is no
change remaining or the change remaining
is too small to core joint further if if
orange does not do any remix thing we
can create a list of corn joins that
orange participated in in this case it's
0 1 3 and then minus 2 and we can do
that for a lot of the participants we
could take yellow for example and see
where yellow participates and then map
out that list of coin joints and then we
could do that for other participants and
then what happens is is if we observe
someone who merges many many coins
together we can ask where which coin
joins to those coins refer to and in
this case we might see someone who's
merging coins that come from
point 1 2 3 & n minus 1 and the output
doesn't really matter so I just left it
as a Big O and so the result is that if
we just look at purple red and yellow we
can see clearly that only yellow has
participated in the in those coin joints
so it's it's it's it's more likely that
yellow is the is the individual that
sent the money and not red or purple so
we could reduce the number of people
that that it could be and that's a
problem with consolidation generally in
particular when users don't remix their
coins so yeah and notice that it could
be the case that there are a hundred
participants in a coin joint and that
the coin joint is completely secure but
you still need a trustless secure
private method for consolidating your
coins when when you exit so yeah so oh
come clean and say that I read the
entire paper and I think I understood
most of it but I didn't come up with any
sort of slides to explain much of it I'm
hoping that if others have read it
they'll have some good questions but
that's pretty much where I'm going to
leave it off here I'll say in summary
the idea of cash fusion is to allow for
users to participate without a
coordinator to have an arbitrary number
of inputs and outputs such that many
users that do want to consolidate or
even do something like a like a spend or
just consolidate can do that and hide
amongst each other so it's sort of a
complementary feature to a conjoint
protocol it's something that would add
to something like a shovel so yeah I'll
leave it at that and I'll let jonald
jump in and say anything he wants to and
get questions going Thank You Levi
senior we're really busy working on the
DC next year okay yeah
soon god super lost in the DC Nets so I
really apologize guys that I didn't have
slides but yeah I would like to ask you
something it's it's stealing the program
spaces that yeah in an interview with I
think between spice with you that you
said that originally you create the cash
fusion II because you wanna the fate of
consolidator cash shuffle old boobs but
it kind of ended up being it's it's own
larger thing yes correct
yeah so when we first developed cash
shuffle the problem that we noticed in
practice right away was getting a you
end up with a lot of coins in your
wallet and when you spend them together
it kind of ruins the privacy so I'm I
think it's kind of the maybe it's the
same exact thing that Aviva was
explaining with with the the math or the
set diagrams would have really had those
symbols what he was talking about but it
basically the problem in cash shuffle
was that when you you know you end up
with with two points one's an anonymized
point and the other is like a change
output that's trivially linkable back to
the input amount so because of that
linkage it just causes a problem when
you combine the coins because there's
too much information that's kind of
leaked out so the idea was to let users
consolidate their coins but it's a cash
fusion kind of turn into more than that
as far as it's just this general purpose
point joins in or you can have like any
number of inputs or outputs the Guinean
house may be it may be a follow-up
question to this directly
is that a common input of the or
historical ownership of the input in a
quadrant specifically can be done with a
subsets and analysis of the change ID so
if LSS
inputs and she gets the equal value
output and a change then of course the
change plus the equal value leads to the
sum of all of your notes and and does a
cat fusion defend against this to that
if you have a change
it cannot be linked back to the inputs
yeah sort of the way that we did it is
we kind of use this like arbitrary
amounts type of approach so that there
really is no clear way to figure out you
know the how the inputs line up to the
outputs it's just just based on this
combinatorics math as far as if there's
you know a huge astronomically huge
number of different partitions so it's
really hard to figure out how things
line up well and there could be multiple
ways that it can blend up so you're not
really isolate and say oh this this
change input goes with this or this
change output goes with this input that
sort of goes that sort all goes away
when you have this you know you're
looking at a transaction with the same
80 inputs and 38 outputs and I thank you
I just would like to know that this is
actually going to be the topic of the
next next research conversation so it's
but they're not going into the
combinatorial he's gonna need to be
always session there that's like it's
kind of interesting when we were first
looking at this most of the people that
were involved in testing cash flow phone
stuff with the other developers we were
focused on on that side of things like
the chain analysis side and I started
thinking about the other side of it like
how do you coordinate it so when you
have like in cash off we had this um I
guess you guys called it like an onion I
guess you know I just felt like
encrypting layers or whatever but so the
problem would be if you have like
multiple inputs
then by the time you peel all the
unlucky layers away you're left with
individual buckets but all of them each
bucket has inputs that obviously go
together or you could have like each
input be wrapped in its own onion layer
but then you can't really tell like who
the who's the culprit if someone doesn't
sign one of the inputs so I started
thinking of look at how can we have the
system or like you know have some kind
of system where we'll be able to blame a
participant that doesn't sign all their
inputs while at the same time and hiding
the information of what if what it puts
are linked together and so and so what I
came up with was this idea of kind of
everyone's just checking everyone else
so if you imagine Li 10 people 10
players if they're all in a room
together standing in a circle it's like
hey here I'll give you one of mine you
give me one of yours she gives me one of
his and so on and and then so initially
I think I can see that it's kind of like
a grid where it was like player wild
check player two's input or first and
button in player two would check letter
three is that ended up getting abandoned
in favor of just like a purely random
approach so everyone there's just like a
random process of like every every input
and output gets assigned to someone to
check in case there's like you know if
the transaction doesn't work and then
you got a check check them all and see
see who's to blame something that I
found very interesting in phase one
which is the set up and waiting list is
that you have different output tiers and
then maybe to summarize that in please
correct me if it's wrong is then a user
can register for different of the tiers
at the same time and each output here is
the value of Satoshi is in the output of
this coin joint and as soon as one of
these ultimate tears gets filled up by a
sufficient number of users this is the
tier valuev being chosen for the
following round and all the users who
have wrapped
for several tears are removed from these
tears that are not that are not being
done yeah so um it's a good question so
in in cash shuffle things are a little
bit more simple or so you can we had
like a round on each order of magnitude
so if you have a coin you know like a
point 0.1 coin or a 0.01 Kohinoor point
all one point each of those forms a tier
and then infusion I guess this is kind
of Mark's work he he come arranged it
more from like an exponential
distribution point of view where the
amounts because the amounts are non
standard they're all kind of within like
a an exponentially random range so you
could have like a like a point one tier
but it also accepts like you know a coin
that would be point three or one that's
point zero seven or whatever and then
what with all these protocols how it
works in the wallet is we freeze the
coin when it's starting to go into
around so when you're just waiting for a
round to start I think the coin will get
frozen but then yeah then the Ravel
started then you'll just the you'll kind
of remove yourself from the other tiers
because that coin is is being used
already
okay thanks and then a follow-up
question would be at the in the paper it
only says example also for example
10,000 Satoshi's or 20,000 satoshis but
I'm a bit confused if this indicates a
range select 10,000 zatoichi's plus
minus 2000 or something because it does
not indicate the equal amount right
because there is no equal amount in cash
yeah so I guess that's uh I guess that's
the amount of the output like roughly
roughly speaking like you know is in it
is it ten thousand satoshis doors at 100
million satoshis so you kind of want you
don't want like one guy with a huge
point to try to mix in with other people
that are using tiny
coins because then his pants will stick
out so you want everyone to sort of be
at least to the bumper right yeah all
right thank you
so this is phase one the clients connect
to the server and download the list of
parameters and and and a figure out
which which tire they wants to go let's
go to face to down which is starting the
round what's what's happening here it's
in phase two the clients send no the
server send a message to the clients
which is which contains around public
key twenty-three unique nouns and the
location of where the chord submission
should be later me I have I have some
questions for this so this 23 nose here
what should this be yeah so this is all
all this non-stop non-stop is part of of
using blind signatures so one particular
challenge maybe I should just explain
the background why why we're even using
those blind signatures so because the
interview can get there but what that
with yeah the thing with like having
multiple outputs it's not like an input
where if you don't actually include an
input
it'll just fail because I um think about
this yeah it's okay if you include extra
inputs it doesn't really matter but if
you include extra outputs as we all know
the inputs that can't be greater than
can't be less than the outputs so how do
you prevent someone from including an
extra output and still blame them so
what we did is kind of create these we
call them like like a submission token
we
had a token to submit your your
transaction component so the server
provides these nice points and then the
client prepares a blind signature
request using that novice point and then
the server will will complete that that
request and sign it and then the client
will unblind it and then permit have
that signature to present with the with
the transaction component so it's a
little bit complicated to think about
but basically it's just like it's like
it's like you're you're signing or the
server's signing that you're allowed to
submit something and then when you
submit it it knows that it's it's valid
so it prevents the these are from
submitting like too many inputs your
outputs you have to submit exactly 23
component to your inputs and outputs or
a blank does that make sense
I know it's a little bit abstract but it
makes sense for me at least you know and
the second thing here is that there is a
the there is a location where covertly
later the components has to be sub me
dead but why why do you need the
different location aren't you assuming
that that you're using you tor streams
and this is where you know what I mean
like is it it's up to this point are you
on the creative net or or what's going
on here um so okay yeah there's covered
announcements of the transaction price
and also covered announcement of the
signatures but there's also like a clear
that connection as far as like if the
client just like loses their internet or
something then we know that to just we
can just disconnect that player there's
a couple other things like that not
everything is done over tor look it
doesn't need to be it's just there's
some advantages to just having just
having the regular connection like and
like for example in the blame phase like
if you don't send your blame in time or
something
we just know to keep that player so it's
like from to her van like timeout
attacks and stuff like that like like
denial-of-service about timing out
so not everything depends on the
torquing action we just make sure that
the the purpose the tour connection is
so that the server can't group
transaction opponents by their IP
address and wouldn't that leads to cross
referencing so for example in this round
these inputs participated and in the
next round totally different inputs
participated but you could
cross-reference that hey there must be a
link between this round and Israel
because there was the same IP
or-or-or is is this something like like
every client that's online at the time
is is is doing distinct so our not overt
or or or it just you know what I mean
yeah so okay I think I can't understand
what you're getting at so you're saying
that if if this if there's some like 10
players and one of them drops out then
we could see like which which
transaction components that they were
and can the server can kind of link them
together yeah I think there's a there
aren't there are only things like that
there's a couple ways that that those
kind of things can be mitigated so one
is each you should really have a lot of
in TX on your wall and each time there's
an infusion like a different random
subset can be selected the other the
other thing is just doing multiple
fusions so you know the user should
never depend on like a you know a single
fusion for their privacy it's always
it's always possible that people could
end up just like consolidating all of
their coins like if five or six players
all happen to spend all of their outputs
it would reduce the privacy for that
round so in the
- because you know the fees are low now
if we can we can afford to do that just
just rely on multiple rounds to permit
those kind of things but it's like you
know it's not perfect sorry I that's not
really what I meant and I cannot claim I
fully understand the fact you mentioned
there but what I meant is that if I
participate in this round and I
participate in the next one and I
participate in the rounds tomorrow then
the server would know that I
participated in these rounds mm-hmm okay
but it wasn't really know which which
come which inputs rapid four years in
that round yeah yeah that's correct but
yeah I guess I guess though there's a
lot of things that a malicious server
can do I think we we talked about down
the spec I mean theoretically the worst
thing that it can do is just kind of
have a custom back again where every
person is kind of like getting extreme
Sybil like just kind of isolated and put
in with with fake play other players
that are controlled by the server so I
think those kind of problems only get
solved at scale when there's just a lot
of people participating and there could
be other things like proof of
participation or whatever but yeah
there's there's definitely some
shenanigans that that a malicious server
can do we just you know we just tried to
solve them them as best we can as far as
preventing the server from from
trivially spying and yeah these kind of
things that you're talking about are
still possible to try to try to gain
information over multiple rounds and
hopefully no one no one malicious is
running the server but you know there
can be SQL there can be multiple servers
so
okay thank you and not of you that you
also bring up you know time altered
access to knowledge service what I
noticed is that throughout the paper and
starting in Phase two you mentioned
these time off periods after which there
aren't either successful or or abandoned
and they're they're all within seconds
and know from experience in wasabi we
only have three phases and each of them
takes several minutes and still many
users do not respond to time because of
for example like a broken tour or
something or tortuous latency so how did
you come up with these timeouts that let
the specific value of them hmm yeah
that's probably more of a question for
mark who did the did yeah tool coding on
this I'm not sure what you guys are
doing it's taking minutes but I think
one thing that we did to speed things up
is to like establish all the tour
circuits like ahead of time and kind of
get them ready and and then things get a
lot faster and it probably also Mesabi
there's a lot more players I'm not sure
I've looked at some of the transactions
there's they look they look pretty huge
but usually like at least so far in our
testing there's been like somewhere like
six to nine players or something like
that so it's not it's not too bad as far
as latency but I was surprised also a
little bit as far as just how well it
does work mm-hmm one more thing someone
won walking in Wasabi's that we don't
have a you don't have a communication
where the set was the server initiated
it's it's always like HTTP requests you
know like you ask for something from the
server and the server replies and and
this way when the server would have to
initiate something then you always have
to wait for the clients to actually ask
for that thing so that that takes time
it's it's not because it's not
possibility it's big or or it's
doesn't make sense to help it but it's
because it was very hard to implement
and I failed in it so so that that that
makes it longer but yeah well we're also
using like website P 256 so that's like
it makes signing way faster especially
so when you have these transactions that
I with lots of inputs and yeah just it
just runs way faster with the libtech
library I think I think the guys from a
left arm first implemented that and we
saw the difference that can speed
calendar ported ported that back to
electronic cash and you can blink sorry
that like a huge transaction with we
have to sign for like 50 inputs or
something like that would take like 30
seconds and then now it takes like one
second or something so that helps all
right thank you
let's go to phase three which is player
commitments it's a very interesting face
all right so as far as I understand it's
about this in this phase the players are
sending their commitments to the
transaction components to the server and
they are sending these invite chunk so
it's not like they are sending these one
by one in different over different or
circles or anything like that they are
sending this in in one chunk and what
are its commitments this is a lot of
components but basically it's these are
ashes to a bunch of things like what but
you will need later to measure the trust
lessness anything you would like to us
to this face well it's not really that
complicated it's basically just you know
the basic idea is then you take your
component which is either an input or an
output and you just hash it so
so the hash forms like a commitment and
that way you can check later if the
actual input matches the hash that you
said it was now the reason you need to
salt it is because there's just not that
many so you could do like a you know a
brute-force lookup or whatever you call
a rainbow table you just hash every
input all right you know I've really put
some outputs in just get all the hatches
and you can reverse lookup we very easy
so that's why you need to salt it and
then there's this is kind of touching on
some of the other phases but that
someone could theoretically cheat by
trying to use the same salt so to prove
the salt is unique y'all suck the salt
the hash and pairing that with when you
when you submit the input that basically
is just as often hash in this phase okay
okay very much thanks and the question
is the salt is unique for every
component yeah just a random 256 bit
number yeah every component gets a
different salt all right thank you so
let's go through these yes no I was
gonna say otherwise if someone could
like if when it comes to the blame phase
of someone new the salt then they could
kind of reverse lookup blanco you all
the other stuff so they can try that
salt number button everything and learn
a lot about the about the linkages
between the inputs so yeah that's why
every everything gets its own unique
salt okay so if this for other server
actually this is kind of phase 3 - right
it's it's it's a response to the
previous message with the right
signature is that is that correct or
there is something in between in phase 4
so yeah like that's just basically
oh wait what do we blind here you're
blinding the knots point I believe okay
yes okay so we are blinding the 23 knots
point and we are getting a blind
signature for that yeah yeah there's
something I want to know that it's
actually very good would be a very good
if we would want to work with the
current wasabi model that would be a
very good extension to that that what
what we also realized that we don't
really have to blind their outputs
because right because we blinded the the
output addresses and you don't really
need you can just blind like like
anything and and you can use that
anything to to to do stuff later around
the server
maybe this is just that quick good
comments and finally a face 5 we have
the court announcements of equal set of
rules now in cash future we have you've
called the component and the component
could be an input component you know the
component or a blank component but
everyone has to submit 23 of them it
doesn't matter at what ratio you have to
serve me 23 of them and as I understand
you are submitting everything correctly
over new surf quits right so there is no
there is no no linkage between these
components right what right right you
can get intellect all the session about
torn whether certain edge nodes are
gonna be us or something but yes isn't
working
shouldn't no linkages yeah I think that
that's more reasonable to consider both
practica then and also if they deserve
to be over accidents anyway yeah yes
yeah every 23 Massachusetts is another
different circuit I'm sorry you say a
corporate announcement of inputs and
outputs and phase 5 and then phase 6 are
actually sharing the components a silver
see difference between announcing and
sharing the components sharing is just
the server guess but has everyone's
components I just sent it back everyone
so then everyone gets a copy variances
of the SS yeah you just get into physics
and so your physics the server so the
server suffers the components and it
shares the components with everyone like
one the components meet all the clients
but in a wait are we sharing the
components yes yes so so so so yes
you're assuring the components not the
commitments okay so we are giving all
the components to everyone that's suffer
correct right yeah so the players send
the components the server and in Phase
six the server sends all the components
back to everyone and then in face seven
we signed them mm-hmm yes that phase
also uses toward this we just call
Coburn s so we cover Lee now stay on the
center's then then the server has all
the senators and it can put the whole
transaction together which is basically
the face
thank you so that was fees eat executing
the transaction yes so from here on
things are kind of falling into place
the X of the accept blaming phase which
you so everyone has everything but I got
to go into the blaming phase I would
rather just ask questions there because
that's D because at the beginning I
thought that it's a really interesting
approach and quite honestly that gives
me a headache that that the people have
to share we share things with each other
with Rondon peers it gives me a headache
from an implementation point of view
that we don't right now and I'd never
done that but but anyway the the problem
I thought there is first is that of them
the random players actually learn stuff
but then as I was reading forward and
they don't really learn stuff because
there's some interesting attraction
between the server and players that this
is not even the players learn is that
correct interpretation doing this yeah
yeah yeah because when the players are
verifying it during the blame phases
they're just verifying one component at
a time and and the no one knows don't
even have the list except the server of
the link now the commitments so the
server knows that
and here's Alice's 10 - terminus but the
other players don't know that so they're
just looking at one
component at a time they all can't
verify these eight components but they
don't know which players maybe it
corresponds to maybe three of them are
from one guy and two of them are from
another maybe they're all from different
people no one really knows
and so by keeping that list only on the
server it it prevents the players to
learning anything and then the server
itself doesn't work is it's not
participating and doing those doing
those checks the only time the server
Lauren's is when someone gets blamed
then it circuit reveals like they can do
this is Alice's transaction that got
blamed but oh just learning what
analysis inputs doesn't really tell it
anything just give me any information
yeah thank yes so you are leaving soon
and I want to give others the chance to
ask questions to not just us but before
that I I want to close this sweetie meet
meet meet at court which is either from
you or mark I did not check but I think
it was very very instructive in in a way
that that that is very practical so on
the design trade-offs parties when
making design choices in this situation
there is trade-off between matching tiny
security costs versus of the complexity
and unreliability in the form of more
protocol faces one must first understand
that even with a perfect fusion protocol
civil attacks are possible and can be
taken to the extreme if the server is
malicious many of the trade-offs start
around the server when judging the
merits of a security trade off it is
helpful to compare what the security
hole allows versus the existing
attacking vectors which may be we
already large out of surfaces so yeah
that's
that I think this is a great example of
whom you come out and and actually talk
about the big picture but let's with
many papers just loose this one tough
diamond in papers I think it's really
insulting so thank you and Igor Aviv
Volker Raphael please join in if you
have some lots of questions I had a
question just about sort of
implementation if there's any intuition
that you have in terms of how long it
would take for the protocol to to go
through and how it scales with more
participants with more inputs and more
outputs if there's anything you can say
about that you should go through so so
let's suppose there are ten participants
with with ten coins each do you have an
estimation of how long a protocol like
this would take - from the time of
chairs establish connection to the time
the coin join is is is broadcasted so
you're so fun practice it seems like
it's not taking very long maybe like
less than 30 seconds and that's with
maybe like seven or eight people it
could take longer if there's more people
and especially if there's rounds where
where players get kicked out so we do
the thing this is kind of an idea from
coin shuffle plus classes just kick one
bad player out and just continue with
one one fewer in the red the size little
brown so if you had like but another
like 15 people and then you had to redo
it for 14 and 13 and so on it could add
add time to it but I think it's like
it's still gonna be like on the order of
like a minute 2 to 2 or 3 minutes or
something maybe faster
and so does this scale linearly do you
think or oh it's really good question I
think I know I have to think about it
seems like it would scale hmm maybe I
have to scale better than here because
there's there's like it's kind of
happening in parallel like everyone's
kind of signing it on their own
I like the client sided so if you had
more clients it's not necessarily going
to take longer
yeah but I don't think about a little
bit more so because things are paralyzed
unlike cash shuffle if I'm not mistaken
which is sequential then there's no
issue there but with more participants
it's more likely that one of the
participants will by accident go offline
yeah so and you're saying that it's it
would probably be linear in terms of
number of malicious peers or
accidentally malicious peers yeah you
bring up an interesting point like with
so one point I was considering the idea
of like we could just use layer
encryption instead of using tor but like
you said that that doesn't scale or it
takes longer than more people you have
so that that's kind of like goes back to
the part of the spec that then if I was
reading about as far as the trade offs
like you can you could have it maybe
better than tour but if it's gonna if
you have to wait until 500 inputs and
outputs get decrypted based on like an
onion scheme then that's gonna take a
long time so yeah I don't answer your
question oh yeah I'm not gonna ask more
because I want the other guys to ask so
now's your chance okay no question of
guys
yeah go ahead because I have a lot and
only five minutes left
okay so just quickly I wanna thank you
that you put this on eater because many
of the researcher
you just can't contribute and it is
really bad even the alters cannot change
when they make a mistake later on the
day publish it and they are not able to
modify the very search so that's another
Skinit contributor you cannot see the
reviews so thank you for that or on the
follow-up notice that I actually done a
couple of typos fixes and you guys were
replying on on eat robots did not match
my typo fixes so but yeah thank you guys
for like help me on the call being
interested in the protocol it's kinda
people from different block chains can
you know can be friends and collaborate
now you know privacy is more important
than any of the egg office and it's it's
it's it's quite a shame and when to do
projects go against each other just
because they have different philosophy
yeah and I thank you very much
so as a summary I would say it's it's
very interesting protocol with a lot of
ideas in it and very complex I would not
go one as as it is and try to implement
it because I'm afraid I would I would
figure out too late things I would try
at first to come up with the easier
scheme that's was the same problem
and if I end up not succeeding in that
then that's when I would look into this
but there are some very interesting
ideas like what we didn't even talk
about the whole pretense of the token
injure that the D server doesn't like
that that's actually a very important
idea that the T vanta album it was was
fighting with the exact same problem and
even we were fighting with the exact
same problem in in Serbian our or so
notion was like just waste a lot of
benefit so yeah so thank Thank You
Jerrod and similar things like you could
theoretically just not get the blame
stuff and just kind of either hope it
works or if it doesn't work you just
retry the just retry with you know the
holding around and eventually it will
work but we wanted to try to take on the
challenges of putting that you know ante
TMS stuff kind of least just having a
foundation to be able to do some of that
the nd that I think yeah I think there
are a couple very good ideas in here and
one thing that I'm still curious about
is is in the worst case during the bling
face who learns what about the other
participants right so so and there's
there's a random peer which will verify
the component but he cannot link all
these components together so even even
the the peer verifier cannot cluster
these components and thus coins and
however oh yeah if the server does not
take part in this playing face so he
does not get individual no server does
get individual components - so the third
Thursday there's a communication key
with every every component so if Alice
is supposed to submit it like a proof of
correctness to let's say Bob she's going
to
years Bob's communication key and and
set then sent her information to Bob now
Bob gets and so she encrypts it everyone
everyone but all the players can see
that there's an encrypted message from
Alice which is supposedly her correct
so if Bob then says that they serve her
this is not a righty he shares that
private communication keen with the
server the server I can see what Alice
actually sent and decrypt it to see if
it was correct so no one except the
server knows that the key is actually
Bob's per se warehouses corner quarter
well they just the other players just
see that there's some component being
verified and it's not everyone's kind of
trusting the server not to be disruptive
so if the server says that hey this
didn't come up for over to kick you out
you know everyone's trusting the server
not to like you know like intentionally
cause issues with it working okay that's
very interesting
yeah even if a user collaborates or
colludes with the server and both are
malicious because they commit to you
know the randomness upfront in the blank
face they cannot really choose who will
be part of a flaming whom I think the
essential components to amongst peers
and so this means if there's for example
one malicious user at the malicious
server they still only know the linkage
of all random components and not enough
of all from one user so I think even in
this case if there's only one or like a
couple issues users collaborating with
the server I think it's the whole top of
privacy yeah there's like a couple more
issues users
as there can be there can be multiple
people that end up getting their
components chapped and when they send it
back to the server the server can kind
of try to match like oh these three were
from Alice so maybe a little bit of
information but then again the server
can also traveler that just just by
controlling players anyway just me so
nothing that nothing was really gained
too much yes okay well well thank you
very much for joining us here on the
phones very helpful it's all scripted at
the insights from the author's and just
more context of the papers so thank you
very much for joining and thank you goes
around yeah
thank you so much Donald we appreciate
it
well we'll talk again yesterday
just a reminder next week we're doing
the combinatorics bit so a job well that
will let the authors know that if they
would like to join us again they can
they can join us again for that okay
all right so Raphael you had some things
to say could you go ahead no I didn't
actually I was just telling you to go
ahead and ask your questions all right
okay so let me see you know since he
left my crush just seems really boring
at this point of time but oh you've
wanted to talk about Peter about the
question four plus plus mmm Alif Oh
okay this'll be e for three months okay
so let me see what else do I have here
Oh y-yes so tomorrow is tomorrow
next week is going to be just a bit of
scheduling is the is the last
agreed-upon topic and from there on
do you guys very and he may be agreed
upon the direction right that we are
going into the organization and the
unequal inputs and try to the
terroristic sand and who s maybe just
looking to block generally this paper
and and try to get the blockchain
analyzers guest on the show that would
be really fun and quite unique what do
you think about this yeah you know
actually I think talking about
heuristics would be very interesting and
a good summary for that might be the
Bitcoin privacy lucky which possess or
the Bitcoin we keep of the chapter on
privacy which asks all heuristics very
well curated and explained so that might
be a good one week discussion to talk
about all the heuristics mentioned in
there yeah
that's good anyway then the next week
this week we're is going to be cooked
cache fusion or not really catch fusion
but crash fusion brought up this
conversation so it's going to be one one
paragraph one chopped one paragraph of
paragraph of cache future the
combinatorics port and there is a lot of
online discussion if that can work that
way or cannot work that way I gather all
the resources I've seen a bit kind of
mailing list and and some medium
articles so that will be very
interesting to see if we can we can get
to the bottom of it if really hope a
good knife conjoins work at what
conditions so that will be next week so
aviv are you back already
and here so you won't have to talk about
Croatia for plus plus briefly but what
team did not appear so I guess you
didn't force it do do you have something
to discuss there yeah so what I would
really like to know and what I couldn't
personally figure out was how a DC
Network could could completely avoid
collisions and have all participants
be able to submit a message so what I
really wanted to show is that three
participants using this you know you
know Tim's DC network could actually do
this and I tried it very I tried it for
a very long time
I actually replicated the the
finite field using using AES because
it's it's an 8-bit finite field and and
I was trying to show that this could
work for a small 8-bit message a single
byte and I and I couldn't do it
the problem that I get is that when he
does this power sums and then he uses a
Newton's identities to create this
polynomial
I only ever get encrypted messages as
the as the interest intercepts of the
x-axis so as far as I'm concerned you
know I'm struggling to replicate this I
reached out to Tim he gave he gave a
good explanation as well as code in C++
and you've all said he's happy to help
me replicate with with the with the code
but I would have to understand the code
well enough to understand how it works
because from from where I'm sitting what
Tim Ruffing the claims he made sound
like magic to me because he essentially
says that three people who are
submitting encrypted messages three
times you can do this magic on it and
then it creates a polynomial where the X
intercepts are the unencrypted messages
and to me this just can't believe it
until I see it and I still haven't seen
it yet so that's where I am if anyone is
familiar with with with this problem and
can help them please do but that's where
I am yes I would ask Mac sex pants to
you respect the authority of the chief
wizard of the Quinn Tim is Right a force
now I think you are ready to do ahead of
us to be ah yes
I got really happy when I get the
holistic understanding of Croatia but
yeah yes to the month is like it's
amazing yeah well because the thing is
is that a collision-free DC network is
very important for us as a tool even put
everything else in control plus plus
aside that's a pretty cool tool and we
don't know when we'll need it so at a
minimum we should understand that tool
well enough that that you know I should
be able to tell and talk to Lucas or you
and explain in a way that we all
understand how to do this and currently
it's still magic to me like I'm actually
not even convinced it'll work but maybe
it's just too too complex it's above my
pay grade so to speak in terms of the
math but I'm trying hard to understand
well you see just just in general there
will be times when we will have to go
very deep into the bottom of the things
like we are already going much deeper
than any other like podcasts or
discussions but for example the not suck
paper I would really prefer if we spent
one more week on it because I was I was
writing code for 1/10 and then oh my god
the third algorithm and the second
algorithm was buggy and you know it's
like I'm still not communist the do not
suck paper actually works or what's the
unit we shown there but but the show
must go on the there is a new topic
every week and and in the end it's more
effective if we if we go on until all of
us decide to okay let's now double down
on this great idea because this is this
is something
and I don't feel like that that kind of
idea the DC Network because it's solving
problems that I don't want to solve
which is the the the ultimate the
centralization or or at least I don't
want to store at this point of time
maybe ten years from now when I become
water and my peers will be longer you
know you actually though what we might
do for next week when we do the
combinatorics of kefir could cache
fusion because it's only one paragraph
in cache fusion this might be worth to
compare to canasa and see maybe where
the differences are right then and just
take this opportunity to double down on
Canasta and look at it again with with
fresh ice so there are there are things
so not suck that maybe I could because
the next week topics is going to be
naive or enjoins
we spark the discussion of cash future
and so estrogen is just one paragraph
but there is a very long discussion on
Bitcoin deaf mailing list okay not that
long but people wrote small no where's
there like in every yeah so that might
be might be hard to understand and also
someone wrote the blog post and actually
some some software to try to verify or
disprove that cream and you know so that
there are content there that the three
can go through and not suck is
definitely that idea okay I promise you
I will try to to to find the interesting
the the relevant paragraphs in enough
suck because yes definitely not suck was
the one who who approach this problem in
a more formal way and that's important
so okay yeah I I feel I will get all the
resources together and people we are
nowhere to talk
now if you want to reply to the pics two
things before right yeah that's why I
think it's okay to stop recording right
yes